The Headlines:
Tragedy on the fairways as
Minister Esmond Wan
suffers two strokes…over par.
The Football Association
heads to Iceland
to learn about their success
in the game.
And the spat between
neighbours in Jurong
threatens to de-stabilise
the entire estate.
Hello and welcome to The Noose.
I’m B.B.See…
And I’m Xin Hua Hua.
Hey ladies,
can I tie your shoe lace?
Because I can’t have you
falling for anyone else.
Oh, for goodness sake.
Topping the Noose tonight:
Tragedy struck this afternoon
as one of Singapore’s political elite,
Minister Esmond Wan,
was hospitalised following an
incident during a routine
weekly high-level ministerial meeting.
That’s right.
The Noose is continuing
to get updates from the hospital
as the story develops,
but right now we can confirm that
Minister Esmond Wan
suddenly felt dizzy, collapsed
and had to be sent to the hospital.
Here’s Andre Chichak
with more on this story.
Behind me you see one of the most
beautifully-manicured golf courses
of the Parameswara Country Club.
And right here,
on the 15th hole of the course,
is where the Minister suffered not one,
but two strokes, over par.
Esmond is a scratch golfer...
Very consistent player.
I mean, of course,
we’re here almost every day.
For a Par 3 hole like this,
he can get a birdie,
or at least, a par score.
But alamak,
he kena the bunker,
you know.
It was very painful to watch.
When he finished, it was...
altogether 5 strokes.
It’s really teruk (terrible), you know.
I almost got stroke watching it.
Others who saw the minister reported
that when he completed the hole,
he looked visibly uncomfortable.
Unable to deal with the massive
disappointment,
he fainted and collapsed,
causing a ministerial-sized mark
on the green,
which his caddy had to repair.
We spoke to the minister’s
personal physician at the hospital.
Well, it is a good thing that the Minister
received treatment in time.
You see, the anxiety caused
by his poor golf score
actually caused heart palpitations,
hyperventilation and increased sweating,
which, of course,
leads to excess body odour,
which is actually
the cause to his fainting.
The thing is, you know how it is
with these ministers.
They expect everything to fall into place,
so when things don’t, they fall.
What do you mean
I can only choose chicken or fish?
Didn’t my office send you the memo?
Where is my fillet mignon
and kopi luwak?
Hello.
Thank you very much for visiting me.
I want to thank all the Singaporeans
at home for their concern.
Actually, the doctor gave me
one week MC
and said that I can stay here
for one night.
But I think I don’t want to.
The single-bed suite they gave me
is very small and claustrophobic.
Like a jail cell.
Huh!
What do you mean
no more fillet mignon?
Minister Esmond Wan
has since left the hospital
and is now recuperating at home,
taking this time to analyse
what went wrong with his swing.
In the meantime,
Sub-Prime Minister Hantam Bola
will be taking on the Minister’s
empty portfolio.
This is Andre Chichak, The Noose.
We wish Minister Esmond Wan
a speedy recovery.
Now let’s cross over to Jurong
where Jojo Joget is investigating
a neighbourhood spat
that is threatening to de-stabilise
an entire community.
Family disputes are a dime a dozen.
But when an innocent third party
gets dragged into the middle of it all,
you know that the pistol head
has hit the fan.
2 weeks ago, one Jurong resident
found herself in such a predicament
when her collection of prized
hip-hop caps were confiscated.
I live on the 2nd floor
and my friends, Lor Mui and Tai Mei..
they are cousins by the way...
they live on the 10th and 7th floor.
You feel me?
So last time, they used to stay
on the same floor,
but then they fought a lot, so now
Tai Mei has got her own space
on the 7th floor. You feel me?
Oh yeah, but then Lor Mui’s clan,
they have a very strict policy
on One Floor policy.
So you know, Tai Mei and I
sometimes we take part in
dance competitions together, right?
And then one day, she wanted
to return them snapbacks
that she borrowed from me.
So on her way down to my house,
she bumped into Lor Mui’s
dim sum-eating clan,
who took away and confiscated
them snapbacks away from her!
How messed up is that?
My family is very influential in this block.
If you want a sheltered
walkway to bus stop?
I get it done...
by the MP.
If you want a void-deck family event,
I make sure you have a good turnout.
All we ask for, is that you,
when the time comes,
stand by my family and our policies.
we have always opposed people
who have ties
with that black sheep, Tai Mei,
including the dance collaborations.
And I have also told Shaquanda
a long time ago,
to follow the One-Floor policy.
She said, "Yes, okay,"
but she continued to conduct
joint-dance exercises. How can?
Welcome!
I’m so happy that Shaquanda
still wants to dance with me,
even though my cousin is bullying her.
That meanie keeps threatening
my friends to stay away from me
as long as I don’t move back.
I just want friends and
my independence.
Is that too much to ask?
Talks have already begun
to recover the caps,
but the proceedings could take months.
Some sources say
this is Lor Mui’s way
of asserting her dominance
over the block.
In the meantime, Shaquanda’s
keeping her fingers crossed
that the caps will be returned in time
for a televised dance show
on August 9th.
These caps are important, yo.
How else will they know that
I’m the real deal?
Reporting for The Noose,
this is Jojo Joget.
Why does that story sound so similiar
to something else I read about recently?
While he mulls over that,
let’s go for a quick break.
Coming up, the state of football in
Singapore could get a shot in the arm,
thanks to Iceland.
Stay tuned.
Hello and welcome back to The Noose.
Have you ever heard of that game,
"Win, Lose or Draw"?
Well, when it comes to
Singapore’s national football team,
they only seem to know
lose or draw, unfortunately.
In a bid to reverse
the fortunes of the Lions,
the Football Association is embarking
on several initiatives,
including going to places like Iceland
to learn from their experiences.
Here’s Bertha Haryani with the story.
What’s the difference between the state
of football in Singapore right now
and a bucket of poop?
The bucket, apparently.
Dumped out in the early stages of a
prestigious regional tournament recently,
the so-called Lions
are licking their wounds
in what has been a disastrous year
for the national team.
And in the international rankings,
Singapore lies 171st, in position.
And to put things in perspective,
Singapore's Press Freedom Index
lies higher at 154,
which is saying a lot about
the state of soccer in Singapore.
However officials from the
Football Association
don’t seem too bothered
by these numbers.
Well, you see,
everyone is going on and on
about our current low ranking...
171. But so what?
Do you realize that there are
far more countries in the world today
than there were 20 to 30 years ago?
I will give you an example.
The Soviet Union used to be
one big country
and not the 45 countries
that it split up into.
And also back then,
there were far fewer
independent African countries, right?
So 171...what’s the big deal?
However, I understand the
public’s frustration
with the current state of football today.
So let me just re-assure my
fellow Singaporeans
that we are taking measures to address
the recent spate of bad results.
Okay, so everybody just, chillax.
This year, at the
European championships,
while mighty England crashed out
at the group stage,
minnows Iceland made it all the way
to the quarter-finals of the competition.
And this despite the country not having
a professional domestic league.
The Noose understands that
the Football Association
recently sent a team of
officials to Iceland
to learn how a country
with a population of just over 300,000
is punching far above its weight
in the football world.
It was a very good trip.
We learnt a lot.
Like, if you want
to go to the country,
I think the best time to visit
is definitely not in December,
because the temperature
is minus ten degrees.
Alamak, it was so cold,
lucky my two toes
are still inside my boots.
But at least I get to see this...
what...in the sky,
there is this very colorful,
colorful...like rainbow,
but the rainbow is moving.
Ah, northern lights.
They say it’s called northern lights!
I think Singapore must adopt this
and use this for the Singapore NDP.
At least, with the moving rainbow,
very cantik, very nice.
Okay, but what did you learn
about how football
is being developed
or improved in Iceland?
What can we learn from them?
Oh, the football…ah…
not much, ah.
Because the country there is very cold,
then the players,
they have to keep running,
so that they will keep warm.
But down here, Singapore,
it’s already so hot,
if you run some more,
I tell you, you mampus!
So, unless we can change the
temperature of Singapore,
I think there is no point
in trying to be like Iceland.
Okay, thank you for...
for what, I don’t know, but thank you.
Perhaps, Singapore football
could improve
if we only focus on the management
rather than the players.
This is Bertha Haryani
reporting for The Noose.
Oh, there's ice-kacang just behind here.
For 20 cents more,
they put extra corn on top.
The Singapore Fruit Festival
has gotten itself into a jam
with the authorities.
It wasn’t for selling fruits that
were spoiled or out of season,
but rather, their produce was
showing off too much skin.
Here’s Andre Chichak with the details.
Fruits and their skin may be good
for your fiber intake,
but having them on display
may land you a hefty fine.
And that is exactly what happened
to the organisers of
the Singapore Fruit Festival
when they received complaints that
their fruits are revealing too much.
Honestly, it was downright seedy
having all those fruits
showing off their skins!
This is nudity you know!
The Singapore Fruit Festival
should not be a skin fest.
It should be banned.
What day and age do we live in now?
Do we still need to see fruits
with their skin on?
Of course not, right!
Nowadays everyone eats
cut fruits without skin
and if you don’t, then shame on you.
We don’t need to see fruits like those
papaya hanging outside in public.
Those sort of stuff
should be kept in the privacy
of your own home kitchen,
but not in the public!
Stupid melon farmers!
Despite the complaints,
fruit sellers from the Singapore Fruit
Festival, like Mr. Chou Kai Lan,
have expressed concerns
that fruit skin is not only
necessary for a healthy diet,
but is also needed for the
safety of the fruit.
Nowadays, Singapore is
very confusing, you know.
Last time, when I was a landscaper,
people say I cannot touch the flower...
cannot touch the pussy willows.
Then how?
Then nowadays, I become a fruit seller,
then they say it is inappropriate
to show the fruits with the skin on it.
It doesn’t make sense.
You think about it. The skin forms
a natural protection for the fruit, right?
If you drop the fruit, you still can sell
because you cannot see any difference.
Will you buy a fruit without
the skin on it?
Can you imagine the fruit,
without the skin,
gets touched by all these
insects and cockroaches.
Will you buy it?
No, right?
Common sense, right?
Despite the practical reasons
for fruit skin,
the Ministry without Portfolio
has taken action
and implemented new measures.
Actually, the recent event at the
Singapore Fruit Festival
was an unfortunate event.
Here at the ministry, we have reflected
and have come up with some new
solution to prevent further incidents.
Moving forward,
we will be banning the sale of food
with the skin on it.
This does not apply to just
fruits and vegetables,
but also seafood,
for example, crabs.
From now on,
only softshell crabs will be approved
for sale at wet markets,
because that crab...
got no shell.
This new ruling will also apply to
food & beverage establishments,
especially the chicken rice sellers.
Chicken rice sellers, from now on,
will only be able to sell chickens
with no skin on it.
The unhealthiest part of
the chicken is the skin,
so the benefits of not eating it
and seeing it
will be of great benefit.
It will help people with their cholesterol!
But I like chicken skin!
It seems like Singaporeans who love
to complain could use a thicker skin.
This is Andre Chichak, The Noose.
I quit.
Time for a quick break,
here on The Noose.
Coming up,
you’ve heard of Economical Rice.
But now, get ready for Capitalist Rice.
Stay tuned…
Welcome back to The Noose.
It's time for a quick report
from our Japanese correspondent,
Nabuyuki Harry Katashi.
Ah, Minna-san Konbanwa!
Watashi wa Nabuyuki Katashi.
This man, Joe Teo-san
wrote a very passionate letter
against young people getting tattoos.
And I agree!
In Japan, we ban people with tattoos
from a lot of places
because tattoos equals yakuza,
yakuza equals criminal,
criminal equals bad!
We must act now
or else Singapore
will become a lawless gangland,
filled with triads, outcasts,
and shady characters,
like in my manga!
I propose that
Japanese brands in Singapore
come to your rescue!
So to all Singaporeans,
If you have tattoos,
no sushi for you!
no Uniqlo for you!
Without all these Japanese
products in their life,
it is only a matter of time
before they return to the path
of the straight and narrow.
Watashi wa Nabuyuki Katashi,
reporting from Tokyo, Japan.
Let’s go Nuclear!
Singapore’s hawker food
has always been touted
as cheap and good.
But in recent years,
good hawker food
has been harder to find.
And one main reason for that
is that Singaporeans
just aren’t willing to pay more for food,
despite costs constantly
going up for hawkers.
Here’s Jacques Ooi with the story.
Cheap and good.
Singapore’s unique hawker centres
are loved by everyone,
including tourists, locals
and tissue-paper sellers
for their wide variety of
racially-harmonious dishes,
the strong social and communal
aspect of dining with others,
including complete strangers,
as well as being the only thing
they can afford until payday.
But recently, hawkers have come
under criticism
for several reasons
including raising prices
as well as pretensions to higher food.
Nowadays, all these young people
like to eat high-class food,
like Spaghetti Bolognese.
And all the new citizens come here
and open new hawker stalls,
selling the foreign food from
their home country.
I want to eat my authentic
Singapore cuisine,
like the Caucasian eating the
Hainanese western food,
the Penang assam laksa,
and the Klang bak kut teh!
When I first came to Singapore,
wonton noodles cost me only fifty cents,
and the portions were so big
it was really like one tonne.
Nowadays, tissue paper is $1.00!
These days you buy wonton noodle,
the bowl so big like
the high class restaurant,
but then the portions so small.
You think what? Fine dining?
And every year the prices are also raising.
The other day, I saw in the news,
one fellow, he bought the Economy Rice,
one plate, $18 you know!
If I wanted to pay ridiculous
restaurant prices
for food court food,
I would go to Newton Food Centre
or go to Sentosa!
Hawkers interviewed
say that they are facing
increasing cost pressures
due to the rising cost of
basic food items and utilities.
Even if rent is controlled in many
hawker centres here in Singapore,
it is not enough to offset the cost of
operating a business.
Also, many young Singaporeans
do not want to be a hawker...
Oh I’m sorry, I mean hawkerpreneur.
So we interviewed one
in the name of
fair and unbiased reporting.
Bro, please bro.
You know nowadays,
got a lot of young boys and girls
want to become YouTube,
Instagram celebrities,
whole day just take photos, take selfies,
post video and collect likes only.
But who want to come here
and actually sweat it out
and earn a living?
Everybody just want to look
handsome, act pretty
and get all these free staycation
and free sponsorship,
free hotel stays from companies
just by posting photos!
Actually Singaporeans
are all very stingy.
For $3.00, they expect
two bowls of mee pok
and one kilo of fishball.
I even had this auntie
come over the other day,
she told me, “Boy,
I could cook for cheaper at home.”
"Cook for cheaper at home"?
Then go home and cook, correct?
This is the Singaporean attitude.
They expect hawker food
to be very cheap.
It is not cheap...they must
understand the cost of labour,
the cost of overheads.
But they are willing to pay more
for Japanese egg tarts
or all these high class coffee.
Correct or not? Nonsense.
So next time, if I take a selfie
of myself in the shop,
then the rent is free?
Seeing things from
a different perspective,
we have Thomas Friedmee,
who sees Singaporean’s changing
spending habits
as an economic opportunity,
or rather, an economic rice opportunity.
We feel that Singaporeans now
are willing to pay for value,
and we see value in home-made cuisine.
Therefore we are evolving
a traditional Singaporean favourite,
Economic Rice.
So it will be a new version
for a new millennium.
And we will call it "Capitalist Rice".
And all our ingredients is organic,
locally-sourced, where possible,
and fair-trade,
and we are making a massive profit
using taxpayer’s rebates.
Some of our dishes
include our all-time favourite,
fillet poulet avec pomme de terre
dans sous vichyssoise de Safran
des Indes et poudre de curry,
which is this dish right here,
curry chicken with potato.
And also our newest invention,
I believe it will be very popular,
wait for it…
salted egg in salted egg sauce.
This is Jacques Ooi
reporting for The Noose.
Well that brings us to the end
of this edition of The Noose.
Gong Si Gong Si Gong Si Ni.
It's Gong Xi Gong Xi Gong Xi Ni.
That’s what I said.
No, you said "Gong Si Gong Si."
Anyway, I’m B.B.See.
And I’m Xin Hua Hua.
Be sure to tune in again next week
for more of The Noose.
Hey ladies,
you may fall from the sky,
you may fall from a tree,
but the best way to fall...
is in love with me.
Good night!
You’re disgusting.
#bestclosinglineever.
Whatever.