The Headlines:
Authorities have devised a solution
to prevent future MRT breakdowns.
Slash, slash, slash.
Singapore’s retrenchment rate
has hit a seven-year high.
And one policeman
speaks out against the trend
of handsome police spokespersons.
Hello and welcome to The Noose.
I’m B.B.See.
And I’m Xin Hua Hua.
Hey ladies,
if kissing is the language of love,
how about we start a conversation?
Aren’t there already enough languages
for people to reject you?
Now, on to our first story for tonight.
Government authorities have finally
come up with a solution
for the frequent MRT breakdowns...
no, really.
Here’s Bertha Haryani with the report.
The Singapore Trains Department (STD)
has had it with
the constant breakdowns
and its own general inability
to deliver on its most basic service
of getting people
from one place to another
without track faults, train faults,
and signaling interruptions.
Here’s one of the executives
at STD to tell us more.
I am the Chief Transmitter of STD
and also a member of the board.
After an extensive review
of our signaling infrastructure
and aging trains,
we have concluded that
the fault actually lies with…
wait for it…
overuse of the train system.
The network simply isn’t designed
to handle such high ridership.
So the board has concluded that
if ridership goes down,
so will the strain on the network,
and hence the frequency
of breakdowns.
The Government Transport
Authority (GTA)
has been working with the STD
to come up with a solution.
And it appears that the solution
is to discourage commuters
from using the train system
in the first place.
As part of an initiative
to discourage commuters
from using the train system,
the board of STD has decided
to raise fares by 500 percent.
A single trip from Ang Mo Kio
to Raffles Place,
which used to cost $1.43,
will now cost $7.15.
Well, all this train breakdowns have really
wasted too much of people’s time,
and time is money.
So from our point of view,
we believe that
raising the fares for the train,
we are actually going to make it
more affordable in the long run.
Now let me qualify my statement.
As we all know the ERP
system very well
and it is also a very good system,
the increase of the train
fares will result in lesser commuters
and therefore lesser breakdowns.
Now in addition, we are also hoping
that this movement
will give the sandwich class a push,
in buying the car that
they have always wanted.
Now that is an absolutely,
great thing, isn't it?
Oh, you don’t know the sandwich class?
They are the kind of people that
will spend $22 on a sandwich.
While the government recognises
that this move
will likely increase
the number of cars on the roads
due to a mad rush by those
in the sandwich class to buy cars,
it maintains that this is the best way
to solve the problem of
frequent breakdowns.
Actually, now that the train fare
is so expensive,
taking the train is very comfortable,
very fast and very efficient.
Just the other day,
I went to the train station
to buy an EZ link card
to try and take the train.
There was no queue,
and in the train, it was very empty.
There was nobody.
With so few riders
and running under capacity,
how to break down?
I used to take the train
to work every day.
But now that it’s almost
as expensive as taking a taxi,
which is almost as expensive
as buying a car,
I might as well buy a car, right?
I mean...
what’s another loan, right?
Home loan,
renovation loan,
personal loan, car loan.
Don’t even know whether
I can finish paying, or not.
I spend way too much on sandwiches.
Which is delicious,
which is fabulicious,
and stylolicious. Do you want?
I tell you, the tuna
comes from cold countries.
You try, ah! Try!
Try, ah.
The government has warned
that COE prices in the
upcoming months will likely increase
due to a higher demand for cars
from the sandwich class.
What’s new, I suppose?
This is Bertha Haryani,
reporting for The Noose.
Good thing I negotiated
for transportation
to be covered in my expat package.
Wait! What?
You got an expat package?
Yes.
We need to talk about this.
On to our next story.
Good-looking spokespeople, like me,
attract the public’s attention.
But as Jacques Ooi finds out,
this strategy has its own pitfalls.
Throughout the ages,
uniformed personnel have always
been considered irresistible,
with their toned bodies,
well-pressed number 1s
and immaculately-groomed faces.
Even emotionless Singaporeans
are not immune to the charms
of handsome policemen,
as evidenced by the popularity of the...
“Shop theft is a crime”
cardboard policeman,
and the rather youthful auxiliary
police officer,
who checks our passports
at Changi Airport.
While Singaporeans are happy
to ogle at these men in blue,
one prominent policeman
is rather worried by this trend
of good-looking spokespeople.
By only focusing on handsome officers,
you are providing the public
with an unrealistic
expectation of policemen.
Just yesterday, I responded to
a noise-disturbance call
that involved a few youngsters
who were creating a ruckus.
And the girl who answered
the door said,
“Hey, Uncle, don’t bluff.
You cannot be policeman."
"Nowadays,” she said,
“all policemen look like Elvin Ng.”
How are we supposed to
do our jobs like that?
Apart from speaking up on the issue,
Sergeant Dollah
has also challenged the YANDAO,
or Young And Attractive Officers union,
to compete against him
in a one-on-one race
during the annual intra-police games.
This is my way of proving that anything
the YANDAO can do,
we can do also.
You know, my dream is...
for the next SFP,
Singapore Frontline Police,
the spokesperson,
he has to have...
a "dad bod".
Did you know that people with
"dad bods" live longer?
This is the body of a man
who tirelessly provides for his family
and caringly eats his childrens’ leftovers
when they complain that
his cooking sucks.
-Yes...
-Come, let's go.
Oh, start already?
Sorry, excuse me,
I have a score to settle.
While netizens have voiced their
support for Sergeant Dollah’s cause,
the SFP is unlikely to change their
handsome-spokesperson tactic.
If you check the
hashtag #shoptheftisacrime,
you will notice that on Instagram,
November last year,
we had 118 posts.
That is 44 more posts than #DFTRch5.
But actually, what is "DFTR"?
But all is not lost for Sergeant Dollah.
The Police Commissioner
will be issuing a statement,
and commending him for his drive
on the intranet,
as well as rewarding him with
$20 worth of supermarket vouchers.
Yay.
This is Jacques Ooi,
reporting for The Noose.
$20 can buy you
a ten-kilogram bag of rice.
Well, just make sure it’s not plastic.
Okay, no problem.
We’re going for a commercial break,
where you’ll mainly see trailers
of the other shows on this channel.
If you don’t want to see those,
head to toggle.sg/thenoose
to catch up on any past episodes
you might have missed.
We’ll be right back.
Welcome back to The Noose.
Globally, 2016 was a bad year.
For Singapore, it was no better,
as 2016 marked a seven-year high
for the number of workers laid off.
Here’s Jojo Joget with the story.
37-year-old IT manager, Roland Seow,
had planned to quit his job
in December.
But one morning in October,
as he stepped into his office,
Seow was asked to go
to a senior manager’s office
for an urgent meeting.
It was there that he learnt
that he was being retrenched.
Huat ah!
If I had resigned in December,
I would not have qualified
for my year-end bonus.
But because they decided to sack me,
now they have to pay me
eight months severance pay,
one month pay for each year
I served in the company.
So after I clear off all my
credit-card debt,
I finally, can have a staycation,
at Hotel 81.
Huat ah!
According to numbers released
by the government,
the number of layoffs hit
a seven-year high
in the first nine months of 2016 alone.
With economic prospects
looking bleak on the horizon,
more people are expected
to be retrenched in the coming months.
Die!
Sore throat ah, sore throat.
Do you have honey?
Honey plus Tongkat Ali.
Can, ah.
I sound like a frog.
Actually, the Singapore
economy is in deep...
trouble, I tell you.
You know how I know?
Because my esteemed colleagues
told me so.
The problem with Singaporeans
is that they know how
to get from 0 to 80.
But they have no idea
how to get from 80 to 100.
And that is where
you earn your money.
Actually who wrote this
statement, ah?
Can explain to me what
it means, or not?
Still rolling?
I don’t know about 80 to 100...all that.
All I know is...
life is very stressful.
You know,
every time I come into the office,
I have to look over my shoulder
to see whether
my boss is coming to retrench me.
Last time,
I only had to worry whether
he was coming to harass me.
Human-resource experts say
retrenchments,
although painful for workers,
affects employers greatly too.
Whenever they talk about retrenchment,
they always blame it on the employers.
But what can we do?
If I don’t take this drastic action,
I tell you, my business
will bungkus (pack).
I think the last few months
already bungkus (pack).
Not like the nasi lemak,
which is very nice,
but this bungkus (pack) is very horrible.
Just two days ago,
I retrenched another 25 of my workers,
so 25 plus…
I know it feels a bit lonely,
but on the bright side,
I get to save cost on this corner,
where the recreation room was.
Last time, a lot of workers
used to spend their time
at the foosball table,
pool table, don't know what...
PS games...
All kinds of money wasted.
At least now, I don’t have to
spend on that anymore,
and even though I
still hold the title
as MD of this company,
but I get to re-learn new skills,
as a receptionist,
as a delivery boy.
Now I understand the job better,
and of course, at times,
as the tea lady and cleaner.
Excuse me.
Hello, yes?
Yeah, give me ten minutes
and we will deliver the thing to you.
Thank you.
Food delivery. Excuse me.
Hello? Yeah?
Okay, okay.
12 o’clock, I will give you the invoice.
Thank you.
Do you want tea?
Later, I will make for you tea,
but as you see,
spare a thought for people like me.
Hello, yeah?
No, mak, no, no no.
You cannot come to the office.
You stay at home, mak.
I will send the food to you.
Singaporeans are too pampered.
They rely too much on other people
to solve their problems.
Why? Because labour is cheap,
so they no need to pick up
some basic skills.
You see, all these young people,
open stylo-mylo café, hipster café,
but they don’t even know
how to change a light bulb.
They don’t even know
how to turn on the oven
or know what will cause
the power to trip.
Because it’s so much easier
to pick up the phone
and call someone else to help.
Correct or cowrong?
I agree.
Young people, these days,
always want to look cool only.
Like a wise man once said,
"Tom Cruise always look funny…"
What?
Oh, not Tom Cruise.
What is it?
"Torn clothes always look funny,
until your dad gets fired."
Reporting for The Noose,
this is Jojo Joget.
Eh, I still don’t get it.
Going for a quick pee break.
Be back in two minutes.
Thanks for staying with
us on The Noose!
Amongst one of the more
popular items to be put in a bun,
hot dogs are a tasty
and enjoyable treat for many.
But recently, serious debate
has sprung up
over the use of condiments
for this delicious snack.
Andre Chichak has the story.
Long, curvy and meaty.
The humble hot dog is easy-to-make
and provides a tasty package
of carbohydrates and proteins.
But recently, heated on-line debate
has sprung up
about the proper way to
savour a sausage,
with some resorting to outright
saucy remarks.
Recently, discussions on
on-line hot-dog-enthusiast group,
Do Not Cross The Yellow Line,
got really heated
when a local café
started offering ketchup
as a condiment option for hot dogs.
It is understood that members of
Do Not Cross The Yellow Line
have strong beliefs about mustard
being the only sauce used
to dress hot dogs,
and do not condone the use of ketchup.
According to the National Hot Dog
and Sausage Council of the United States,
ketchup is not an advisable
condiment for hot dogs.
You see, we prefer the
time-honoured traditions of using
mustard, relish,
cheese, chilli,
onions for hot dogs.
We are simply trying to ensure
that this meat dish,
that we know and love,
is best appreciated as it was
originally created. Right?
And hence our group name,
which pays tribute to mustard,
not the other thing:
"The Yellow Line".
And it also pays tribute
to our firm belief
that you do not want to cross us,
because if you cross us…
Yes, while the text does say so,
despite the statement from the National
Hot Dog and Sausage Council,
a survey by the Council
shows that 79 percent of Americans
regard ketchup as
an acceptable topping,
and the widespread support
comes, especially,
from Americans between
18-34 years old.
We are not talking about Americans
and their hot dogs;
we are talking about hot dogs
being served in a Singapore-ese café.
I think we should actually look at
global food trends here.
The Chile ones, they eat it creamy
with avocado and mayonnaise...
Hey, hey, no foreign
intervention, please...
-Excuse me, can we please, calm down.
-No foreign intervention!
We don’t want to be too
thin-skinned here.
Okay, fine. Okay, fine.
All I'm saying is that
we should be able to choose
how we want to put meat in our mouths,
without the unnecessary
overreach of civil groups
and all the unnecessary mockery
on social networking sites.
Yes, I understand the distaste
for the taste of tomato and meat,
but honestly, in the privacy
of our homes,
some of us are not above
enjoying some beans with franks
or even some sliced sausage
with baked beans in tomato sauce.
What are you accusing me of?
Are you saying that I cook my hot dogs
on an open flame?
Is that what you are saying?
What the...
And so the debate rages on and
has stirred the pot,
with many Singaporeans chiming in
on flavourial freedom
and that a mandate should
be sought from a legal perspective.
And this seems indicative of
an evolution on both culinary culture
and online behaviour...
Lap cheong for sale!
Taiwan Sausage for sale!
Oh great!
Looks like another fight and
sausage-fest is coming!
This is Andre Chichak, The Noose.
To stay relevant in today’s
ever-changing media landscape,
The Noose is constantly
on the lookout for new talent.
So please, welcome our brand new
Japanese correspondent,
Nabuyuki “Harry” Katashi!
Minna-san Konbanwa!
Watashi wa Nabuyuki Katashi desu.
But since you are all my friends,
you can call me Harry!
Reporting all the way
from Tokyo, Japan,
I am so excited to be one of the
new foreign correspondents
for The Noose!
A few weeks ago, I saw news report
that Singapore now has
its very own vending-machine café,
with machines selling hot food.
Ichiban!
You are only about
twenty years behind Japan,
but it’s never too late to join
the civilised world.
But it’s so funny
because people were queuing
one hour to buy their food.
One hour!
That does not make sense.
If you’re eating from the machine,
means you have no time,
if you have no time,
then why you queue?
I don’t think Singaporeans get it.
Singaporeans not get it...
Watashi wa Nabuyuki
Harry Katashi desu,
reporting from Tokyo, Japan.
Goran itadaki arigatou gozaimashita.
Well we’ve come to end
of this edition of The Noose.
I’m B.B.See...
And I'm Xin Hua Hua,
the man of your dreams.
Good night.
Those dreams are called nightmares.
Not funny, that's an old joke.
That's true.