The Headlines:
Esmond Wan steps forward
to do a good deed
that backfires spectacularly.
And more businesses in the vice
industry are going digital.
Hello and welcome to The Noose.
I’m B.B.See…
And I’m Xin Hua Hua.
Hey, ladies,
kissing...
burns 5 calories a minute.
How about a workout?
As the minister-at-large at the
Ministry-Without-Portfolio,
Esmond Wan has the unenviable task
of dealing with problems that
nobody else wants to deal with.
To understand what makes
this great man tick,
The Noose was recently given
unprecedented access
to his home and family.
Here’s Jojo Joget with the story.
Unlike their Western counterparts,
the families of Singaporean politicians
are rarely brought into the limelight
for political campaigning.
In an unprecedented move, however,
Minister-without-portfolio, Esmond Wan,
is giving The Noose an exclusive,
unfiltered look
into his home and family life.
Actually, my staff and I
have been analysing
responses of Singaporeans
to world leaders
and we discovered
that many millennials
like former US president Obama.
After a year of brainstorming,
we discovered that the solution
is to become more relatable.
And what better way to be
more relatable
than to show that ministers
are people with homes too.
So without much further
ado about nothing,
my name is Esmond Wan
and welcome to my crib.
Please come with me.
This is my living room.
To be more relatable
to most Singaporeans’ living standards,
we downgraded from a
25000-square-foot bungalow
to a 15000-square-foot bungalow.
This is the perfect place for me
to store all my trophies and awards
that I have won since primary 1.
But, like most Singaporeans,
I, myself, have experienced failure.
Just like in primary 4,
when I topped my primary school,
except in moral education.
Please come with me.
This is my sofa.
My family and I like to sit here
and watch "House of Cards"
to experience, with most Singaporeans,
the political intrigue and good acting
that we never get to experience here.
Darling, just in time.
This is my wife, Ching Gek.
Say "hello" to the camera.
Dear, let me finish this first.
As you can see,
as the CEO of Chempedak Holdings,
my wife is very busy.
Check out my Facebook post.
This...post. It's quite funny, right?
This is my casual dining room.
The breakfast nook is around the corner
and the formal dining room
for wine tasting and high tea
is two floors up.
Please come with me.
As you can see,
this is one of the many tributes
I have received
from Singapore’s street artists.
It is a constant reminder for me
to strive to better the lives
of Singaporeans,
because some of them are too poor
to afford Photoshop.
-Daddy,
-Aiyo!
I’ve completed a 50-year prediction
of all the major global and domestic
incidents that will affect your party...
excluding affairs.
Yes.
Top 0.01 percent of her cohort.
She could have attended any
school in the world,
but we made sure she went
to a local university.
Good job, girl...
And this is my master bedroom.
Come in, come in.
Welcome, welcome.
Papa E-dawg in the house, yo!
Yo, yo…
Here we go!
No, no, no, no.
As you can see, we support the Arts.
Cut, cut, cut, cut.
Ah Boy, I tell you not to play
with your money.
Haiya…
The Ministry-Without-Portfolio
is confident
that this “House with Ministers”
strategy will pay off
and intend to let the rest of
Minister Wan’s colleagues
grant the same access to The Noose.
If nothing else, the Ministry promises
that it will be more entertaining
than having the national
broadsheet interview them
in the column “Dinner with Hachiko”.
Reporting for The Noose,
this is Jojo Joget!
Who’s Hachiko, in the first place?
I only know Pikachu.
A recent letter in a local newspaper
made a passionate call
for Singaporeans
to watch more locally-produced
television shows.
As expected, the letter
was ridiculed online
and prompted a debate on
the quality of local shows.
Here’s Jojo Joget with the story.
The humble television
has its place in just about every
home in Singapore,
yet recent studies have shown
that Singaporeans are not
watching enough
of locally-created programmes.
Despite local TV being free-to-air,
Singaporeans would rather
watch overseas content,
as expressed by Mr Chao Keng.
I mean, why watch local shows
when you can watch shows
from over the world?
There’s what...
Korean, American, Thai…
You name it...I can watch it all online.
Anything!
It’s like…why would you
only eat chicken rice
when you can have an
international buffet?
Right? Right...
I recently watched local TV
and it’s just not the same.
It’s like meeting up with an ex.
You are very excited, at first,
to reconnect and meet up,
but then you realise you got
nothing in common.
Then you wonder how the both of you
even fell in love in the first place.
I can’t believe I used to
watch "Crimewatch".
However, there are others,
like Mrs Chap Chye,
who are raising awareness for the
conservation of Singapore television.
Preserving our local television heritage
is of utmost importance!
Singapore broadcasting has been
around since the 1960s.
That’s 50 years’ worth of history
and programming!
Well, most of it is...okay,
but still, it's 50 years’ worth!
Sometimes when my kids
watch TV with me,
they’ll ask me, “Mom, before "Tanglin",
what kind of drama do you watch, ah?”
So I tell them,
“Long before your time,
there was 'Under One Roof'
and 'Phua Chu Kang'.
It was the best in Singapore,
JB and some say Batam.
Come, I show you on Toggle.”
After they watched it on Toggle,
they were very fascinated…
that it was not shot in HD.
So they watch their Korean dramas.
If Singaporeans continue to only
watch overseas content,
then the demand for our local TV
will dry up and disappear forever…
just like 'The 5 Show'.
Or 'Not the 5 Show'.
Despite the decrease in ratings
and audience size,
the future of local television is bright,
according to local
network content creator, Chin.
Look, let’s be real.
Competition is tough, being the only
national broadcaster in Singapore.
Do you know how many
other TV companies
we had to put out of business
so we could survive?
Just kidding…
With regards to the decreasing numbers,
we’re going to make sweeping changes
that will revitalise our company!
Firstly, do you know about 360 videos?
Well, we’re going to have...
720 video!
That’s right, 720 video.
That’s 360 times…
two, yeah.
So for 360 content,
you must move your head or device...
around, once, to see the whole image.
But with our new patented 720 content,
you not only make one,
but two spins before you see
the whole image.
So you’ll get twice the
amount of content
as compared to 360 content!
It’ll make for some very interesting
storytelling, that’s for sure!
We’re also working with the
Ministry-Without-Portfolio
to disable internet access across
Singapore during primetime.
That way, we can ensure
that we’re the only viable
entertainment option
and Singaporeans won’t have
a choice but to watch us!
Well, I think I better stock up
on blu-rays and DVDs.
Reporting for The Noose,
this is Jojo Joget.
Okay, we’re off for a break now.
Coming up, a tear-jerking call
for Singaporeans
to watch more local television.
Stay tuned.
Hello and welcome back to The Noose.
If you’re a business owner,
it’s almost unimaginable to not have
an online presence these days.
And as Jacques Ooi reports,
it applies to businesses in the
vice industries as well.
In our ever-changing
economic landscape,
companies are looking
at ways to innovate
and those in the vice industries
are no different.
To help them keep up with the times,
a prominent local ad agency
is working to give businesses
in Singapore’s less-savoury trades
a facelift through social media
marketing and rebranding.
As Singapore’s premier
social media marketing firm,
we have made it our duty to help local
businesses meet the demands of today.
Some of these trades have been
around since time immemorial.
So what we need to do
is strike a balance
in preserving heritage
and pushing up click-through rates.
After all, I think it’s important
that we help
homegrown enterprises keep afloat.
One satisfied customer of GOODFLUFF
is 52-year-old Kwek Tai Long.
Mr Kwek originally worked
his way to the top
of a local vice conglomerate,
but left 5 years ago
after a management dispute,
to set up his own
money lending operation.
Originally, I named the
company Money4U
because I want my company to be
friendly and straightforward.
But business was average only.
So my daughters told me
to engage Ah Cat.
Ah Cat came in and analyse
and told me that the name was…
was what, ah?
Too generic.
Not good for business.
Sound like those
Ah Beng, Ah Seng company.
Cannot.
Actually, I quite paiseh,
because Ah Cat told me
my name is damn big in this industry
and I should put it in!
We even have a new tagline:
“How to make a KwekBuck with us!”
You get it, right?
Get it, then I want to play pool…
Apart from an extensive online
marketing campaign,
GOODFLUFF will also be creating
original web content
to reach out to a yet
untapped millennial crowd.
The first step?
An all-access reality show
that features Mr Kwek and his two
Instagram-famous daughters,
KinDa and KaiLi.
Everyone thinks that we look like
average Lians, but we’re not.
We are more-than-average Lians.
Both of us graduated summa cum laude
from business school in New York.
So you know we have what it takes
to take vice into the new millennium.
Here’s a sneak peek of the first episode
of this new webseries.
-Daddy
-Yeah..
Daddy…
Don’t anyhow grab my stick.
Jie and I want to talk to you
about expanding our business.
-Yeah, this is my business proposal...
-Our business!
We want to open a club!
Ladies only!
Ladies only?
Then how do I go in?
-You are mummy, what.
-Oh.
The entry requirement is as long
as everyone does this.
Like that, then where they chop?
Chop here?
Must tell your door person to chop here.
-So, okay?
-Okay, can, can...
Wait, wait, wait!
Social media.
Smile lah, Jie.
Everybody one, two...
-Hashtag…KwekBucks.
-Hashtag...RichDaddy.
Not fair, you know!
Life is not fair. It was my pitch!
And then that...stole my pitch, okay!
What is this? What is this?
Anyway, since I’m the youngest,
daddy say must always give in to me.
Everybody, you know what to do.
life is always full of ups and downs,
so you must always stay zen.
And this is how I stay zen.
Everyone,
I love you all.
Sign off, KinDa.
Love you all.
-Daddy!
-What?
Why you change your mind?
Our focus is money lending,
not clubbing.
But you say you will do what I want!
Now, no.
Please, daddy, please…
-Cannot!
-Please…
Please…No!
You everything also don’t let us do.
How you expect us to take
care of the business?
You suck!
Don’t like that.
Smash this, don’t smash my logo!
Daddy, don’t angry. Lai, lai…
'Live', 'live'…Show them.
Zen.
That preview clip alone has generated
a 200 percent increase in
business enquiries from millennials
and a 500 percent increase
in applicants
for the position of ‘runner’ at KwekBuck.
GOODFLUFF is confident
that it can achieve
similar success for its other clients
and take vice in Singapore
to a whole new level.
This is Jacques Ooi,
reporting for The Noose.
Savvy politicians won’t miss the chance
when a good photo opportunity
presents itself.
But as Andre Chichak finds out,
sometimes it can go horribly wrong.
Minister Esmond Wan was on
his way to visit a friend
when he saw something that
affected him greatly.
In the carpark next to his friend’s block,
an elderly lady looked like she was
struggling with a pile of junk.
Minister Wan instinctively knew
that he had to give the
poor lady a helping hand.
And immediately post his
good deed on social media.
Needless to say, it didn’t take long for
netizens to react strongly to his post.
Can you believe the gall of that woman?
How dare she!
Minister Wan tried to help her...
Such a good man, right?
But instead of letting him
have his moment,
she photobombed him instead.
I’m so upset.
My followers are so upset.
We are going to find her
and photobomb her
and upload to FaceTube.
Others also questioned why the woman
did not prevent the minister from
carrying such a heavy load,
given that he was just discharged
from hospital a couple of weeks ago.
So what if he offers you help
to carry things?
You must not tax the poor man.
Since we all know that he
has been sick recently.
He is one of the very few capable
ministers left in the cabinet.
We cannot afford to let anything
bad happen to him.
The Noose managed to track down
the elderly lady in question
to get her side of the story.
I was just carrying my things
from the void deck to the carpark.
It is part of my exercise routine...
every day I’ll do.
Out of nowhere, this crazy man
suddenly come and take
my things away from me.
Then we struggled and I asked him
what he want to take it from me?
He said I shouldn’t be struggling.
I tell him “Sir, I was just trying
to keep fit, you understand?
At my age, I need to do something.”
But he refused to listen.
Then, how come, so nice, just then got
one photographer standing with him.
You tell your minister, want to wayang
also wayang properly, ah!
This is Andre Chichak,
The Noose.
Time for a quick break here
on The Noose.
Welcome back to The Noose.
Several weeks ago, we did a story
on how a once rising star
in Singapore’s athletics scene
faded away due to
his dependence on sugar.
As a result, he made way
for national 100m-record-holder,
UK Shyam,
to be Singapore’s fastest man.
And UK Shyam has now very
generously offered Jamal Hussein
an opportunity to put things right
with a one-off race.
I would say it's a dream come true
to get my race against UK Shyam.
Actually, the dream is more for him.
Jamal was once my greatest rival
when we were 7 years old.
He used to be a stud muffin.
But now he is just a muffin.
He holds the national record of 10.37.
I'm sure that if my running career didn't
go off the rails during my teens,
I would have gone under
10 seconds...easily.
That is very natural.
It's like saying the sun rises
from the east,
the fish can swim, the birds can fly.
I’m not even exaggerating. I’m serious...
below 10 seconds.
I think the only thing he can finish
under 10 seconds is 5 curry puffs.
I'm going to put him out of his misery.
Today, I'm going to put things right.
I'm going to show Singapore
what they missed out on.
My advice is when you watch,
try not to blink.
I had it, man, I had it...
but...you notice something?
He was wearing shoes.
Spiked running shoes, some more.
In kampong days, where got shoes?
Can win, but please, be original, ah.
I'm glad we've finally put
the matter to rest.
I wish him all the best in
whatever he does.
But I hope he stops calling me.
Bravo, bravo, bravo!
Thanks to UK Shyam,
for giving us all hope.
And that brings us to the end of
this season of The Noose.
If you want to see more of us,
head to the Sistic website now
to book your tickets
to the second edition of
The Noose and Kakis Stage Show,
happening from May 19th to 21st.
Farewell, fans, followers and friends.