The Headlines:
Know your limits!
The government rolls out a new
training course for maids.
Thai football fans are up in arms
over a Singapore businessman’s
ownership of their beloved club.
Saving money and lives.
More Singaporeans are choosing
to give up driving.
Hello and welcome to The Noose.
I’m B.B.See…
And I’m Xin Hua Hua.
Hey, ladies,
even if there wasn’t any gravity...
I will still fall for you.
On your face, I hope.
Topping The Noose tonight,
the government has rolled out
a new mandatory training course
for domestic helpers.
That’s right.
The Noose understands
that this course will teach maids
how not to overstep the boundary
in terms of taking over
as parents of their charges.
Here’s Jacques Ooi
with more on this story.
They clean your homes.
They care for your young and old,
and in some cases,
tolerate your
less-than-humane treatment.
With over 220,000 foreign
domestic workers, or maids,
working in Singapore,
they have become an essential
part of the Singaporean household.
But a recent survey has shown that
many Singaporean parents
are becoming increasingly worried
with the idea
that their children are being
parented by their maids.
I first noticed it during
dinner last week.
I was sending out an urgent email
at 11 p.m. to my subordinates
about the virtues of
work-life compromise
when my 2-year-old suddenly
shouted, “Mama!”
At first, I was going to
ask him to shut up
because I thought he
was disturbing me.
But then when I turned around,
I saw that he was calling
out to my helper!
The best part is, my helper didn’t do
anything to correct his mistake!
Luckily this happened at home.
Imagine if it happened in front
of my relatives.
That would be so embarrassing.
Hey, there mate!
I’m a super chill parent.
And I want my kid to be
muchos chillax, like me, too.
But the helper’s like...
“Sir, she hasn’t done her
homework yet, sir."
"Sir, the teachers are complaining, sir."
"Sir, she’s gonna be held
back a year, sir.”
Major kill buzz, dude.
And when I was like “whatever”,
she forced my kid to do her homework
till she pass her exams!
She was so fierce
till she made my little girl cry!
I was like, hello...
Who’s the parent here?
Who’s the parent?
If there is anyone who is going
to leave long-term emotional scars
it should be me, not her.
Not her!
Right!
The Ministry of Maidpower
has heard the complaints of
Singaporean parents
and are implementing a compulsory
course for all maids in Singapore.
This course will ensure that
foreign domestic workers
understand the boundaries
they are meant to keep
when caring for their charges.
Start already?
Actually, the solution is very simple.
The difference between
a parent and a maid
is the amount of discipline
they can dish out on the children.
So now, we are teaching the maids
to issue stern warnings,
but to take no concrete action
against the children’s behavior.
Just like the last time when my son
was ‘reprimanded’
for bypassing the chain
of command to whistle blow.
But for those with younger children
who find it difficult
to understand the difference,
we are now training the maids
to care for them
expressionlessly and emotionlessly.
And to carry them at arm’s length,
so that when they are finally
hugged by their parents,
the children will automatically
love the parent more.
While the course is being
rolled out in phases,
one maid who has gone
through the programme
is exceptionally happy that the
government has made it compulsory.
At first I felt sad,
my employer don’t let me
be close to the children.
But then, now I realise that
children take up a lot of time!
Now, I can finish
the housework by 9 p.m.
and I can sleep by 10 p.m.
No need to read bedtime story,
no need to play with dolls.
I can even watch drama from
my home, Myanmar, on my phone
and then sleep 6 hours!
Good life!
I love Singapore!
It’s still too early to tell,
but authorities are confident that this
course will decrease dependence
on foreign domestic workers
in the long-run,
and increase the bond
between parents
and their ankle-biters...
I mean, their children.
This is Jacques Ooi,
reporting for The Noose.
Oh, those poor parents,
having to look after their own children.
Moving along,
Singaporean tycoon, Valen Seah,
is facing angry calls
to relinquish ownership
of Thai football club Real Patpong.
The club has not won a game
since August last year
and is now in danger
of being relegated.
Here’s Jojo Joget with the story.
Football is a funny game.
One moment you can be a hero
and the next, absolute zero.
But that doesn’t just apply to players.
Managers, coaches and now,
increasingly, owners of clubs too,
are realising that fans
are really like lalangs
that sway in the wind.
Take the example of Singaporean
businessman, Valen Seah.
In February last year, he announced
that he was buying over
Thai football club, Real Patpong.
Upon hearing the news,
thousands of jubilant
supporters of the club
turned up outside the club’s
headquarters in downtown Bangkok
to welcome what they saw
as an angel coming to
the club’s rescue.
Sawadeekup.
We were so happy when
Valen Seah bought the club
because before that,
nobody cared about Real Patpong.
People came to Patpong
only to see ping pong,
see the birds and to see goldfish.
But nobody cared about
our football team.
So, when he announced that
he is buying the club,
Suddenly all the media attention
was on us...
And finally our team got money...
money to buy original football boots,
not the imitation football boots
from Patpong night market.
Our boots super good!
Patpong Patpong Real Patpong!
Fast forward 12 months
and Real Patpong find themselves
fighting against relegation from
Thailand’s premier league division.
Seah has since fired
four coaches in the past year
and the club hasn’t won
a game in months.
Those same fans who once
welcomed him with open arms,
now want him to sell his majority stake.
Valen Seah no good…
I don’t know why he wants
to own the club
when he has no interest in
improving the quality of the club.
I mean, how do you expect
Real Patpong to compete
with the best clubs in Thailand
when the only players you employ
are from the S-league?
They run for 10 metres
and then they rest for 10 minutes.
Valen Seah, please go home...
Go home.
Despite calls to relinquish
ownership of the club,
Seah remains defiant.
Real Patpong used to be one
of the most popular
and glamourous football
teams from the...
70s to the 90s.
But since then, its fortunes have faded,
just like how Patpong itself
has become a gentrified tourist trap.
But I have a dream.
I want to make...
Patpong great again!
For starters, let me introduce our new...
head coach.
Sawadeekup, my name is
Pornsak Sukhumvit.
Well, Valen Seah, good luck.
Reporting for The Noose,
this is Jojo Joget.
What’s up with all these
billionaires buying football clubs?
They should be investing in
more meaningful projects,
like building more gentlemen’s clubs.
Not like you’d be allowed in.
We’re off for a break.
Coming up, more Singaporeans
are giving up driving.
Stay tuned.
Unlike you. You are
driving me up the wall!
Hello and welcome back to The Noose.
One of the quickest ways of
getting richer in Singapore
is to give up driving.
And more Singaporeans are indeed
giving up this expensive habit.
But as Andre Chichak finds out,
money is not necessarily
the primary motivation.
Besides housing, owning a car is
probably the second biggest expense
for Singaporeans who choose to drive.
But even with high car prices
and exorbitant charges
to drive on certain roads at
certain times of the day,
Singapore’s car population
doesn’t look like
it’s going to decrease anytime soon.
However, there is a small but
growing number of drivers
who are choosing to ditch their cars
and go back to using public transport.
Most cite the prohibitive costs
of owning a car.
But for some, like 37-year-old
financial consultant, James Teo,
there are other push factors towards
public transport than just costs.
The high cost of driving
is definitely a factor in my decision
to give up driving.
But it’s definitely not the main reason.
That’s actually, my wife.
Whenever she’s in the car with me,
I cannot take it.
My GPS device
I can ignore or put to mute.
But the human GPS sitting beside me,
I cannot turn off.
“Turn left, Turn left.
Eh, why you turn left?
I told you to turn right, right?
It’s better for my sanity that I don’t drive.
For many families, having a car
is a huge convenience.
Besides ferrying the kids to school,
it also comes in handy
when you have to run errands,
go grocery shopping or
pick someone up from the airport.
However, some say
it’s a double-edged sword.
Honestly, I really don’t mind
driving my family around.
But have you been to a relative’s house
for a function or for a wedding
and there are all these old people...
I mean, people older than me
who don’t drive?
Suddenly it becomes my responsibility
to drive all these people home,
just because I’m one
of the few there with a car.
Then cannot say 'no', what.
Cannot say 'no' what, because of
respect and all that nonsense.
Then who pays for my petrol?
Well, you could just
not attend the functions.
Anyway, The Noose also
understands that
a growing number of drivers
are also giving up driving
because they are very concerned
about the bad driving habits
of many motorists on the road.
Driving on our roads nowadays,
very scary.
Singaporean drivers cannot even
drive straight in one direction.
And then all these smart alec
want to drive against the traffic.
The government should ban
all these video games
that consider driving recklessly as a...
a badge of honour...
my son taught me.
And they should also ban all these
cyclists from the roads.
All these stupiak bugger.
You know what is stupiak?
Stupid and piak you...
I taught you before.
All these stupiak buggers,
say want to cycle to exercise.
If you want to exercise,
you go to a gym.
Why you exercise on the road?
This is Andre Chichak, The Noose.
Growing up in a country of
more than 1.5 billion people,
the concept of personal space
is quite foreign to most of us Chinese.
And given the rising number of
disputes here amongst neighbours,
it seems Singaporeans too
are slowly getting used to the idea.
Here’s Bertha Haryani with the story.
When people live close to each other,
it's inevitable that disputes will arise.
Most of the time, neighbours
tolerate minor inconveniences
that overstimulate one's senses
of sight, hearing and smell.
But once they’ve reached
the limit with that,
they get their members of parliament,
or MPs, involved.
Actually, residents, nowadays,
are very savvy.
If they have an issue
with their neighbours
they will find my email address
on the government website,
cc my boss and all my fellow
cabinet colleagues
so I cannot don’t reply.
Yes, dealing with all these issues
takes time away from my
golf and wine tasting,
but it is essential to deal
with all these problems
to preserve a harmonious living
environment for one and all,
and I, personally, take pride
in dealing with each and every…
What?
Neighbour playing mahjong...
baby cannot sleep.
What's the big deal?
Ask my grassroots leader to deal with it.
Like I said, I always put
my constituents first.
While most are using official channels
to settle neighbourly disputes,
some Singaporeans find that
such orthodox methods
are taking too long to get things done.
Increasingly, residents such as
68-year-old Mr Kow Peh Seng
are taking matters into their own hands.
This estate is damn old.
The people that live here are
either pioneer generation
or those losers that fall short of
qualifying to be pioneer generation.
And then, recently,
these youngsters moved
into the estate...
Say this place has a lot of “flavour”,
got “unique taste”.
Hello, this is HDB.
You think what? Satay Bee Hoon.
And then the newlyweds
that moved into the flat next door...
Every night like their
wedding night like that.
Every night they try to break record
for the highest pitch
the human voice can reach.
Then the pictures on my wall
every night shaking one, you know.
Then you know what the best part is?
My wife come and ask me,
“Why you not like that?”
Apart from making verbal threats,
Mr Kow has put up posters
all over the block,
detailing his neighbours' poor behavior,
thrown chicken blood at their doorstep,
and rung a shame bell
whenever they leave home.
However, the couple in question
remain unfazed.
No! We’re not offended.
In fact, that is the reason
why we moved in.
Yes! I personally feel it is very real
to be engaging with a
wife-beater-wearing elderly man.
Yeah. Our parents offered us a house
closer to them in Bukit Timah,
but we wanted to experience
what is the real Singapore like.
Yeah, I don’t know about you, dear,
but I felt like Mr Kow really
connected with us
when he used that
Game of Thrones reference.
He smeared chicken blood
at our door this morning, you know?
Oh yeah, I took a picture of it.
You see.
Oh, I forgot to post it.
Lucky you reminded me.
Wait ah. I hashtag, artintheheartlands.
Hashtag, chickenblood.
Hashtag yearoftherooster.
So clever.
Looks like Mr Kow will need to invest
in some noise-cancelling headphones
to use for the foreseeable future.
This is Bertha Haryani,
reporting for The Noose.
Time for a quick break,
here on The Noose.
Okay, coffee time.
Welcome back to The Noose.
In a bid to improve security in
government computer networks,
civil servants have been barred
from using the internet.
Andre Chichak visited a government
department recently
to see how civil servants are coping.
What has been a simple pleasure
for many government employees,
will soon become forbidden fruit.
The government has just released news
that it will restrict internet access
to over 100,000 computers
used by public servants by June 2017.
Big news for a small island.
This announcement has,
of course, been met
with a mixed response by the public
and in particular,
government employees.
I spoke to Mr Seow On Seow
of the IDA,
the leading agency for this exercise,
about this major decision.
So, you know, we live in a very
dangerous cyber world, right, Andre?
You know, not me, not you,
but what if, you know,
accidentally, someone,
one day,
go to one of those...
how can I put it delicately…
YYY site.
And then the computer got virus,
and then the virus jump from
this computer to that computer.
Then from there, go to here,
then from here, go to there,
then from there, go to there,
then from there, go to here,
then from here, go to there.
Then how?
It’s very dangerous, Andre...
very, very dangerous.
So we have to be extra careful.
Yes, yes, Mr Seow,
so I understand that your agency
has been on the no-internet trial
for a few months now.
So how has it been so far?
Actually, it has been very
excellent, you see,
You know, our productivity
has gone up.
But we, at first, have to get used
to this spike in productivity.
We are not very used to it.
We don’t know how to manage it.
Ultimately, it’s all thanks to my
excellent, genius HR skill,
that’s why this transition
has been very smooth.
While Mr Seow and his colleagues
may be all praises for it,
there are some voices of resentment.
Our next interviewee
declined to be named.
Eh, tak boleh lah.
How can like that?
What do you expect me
to do the whole day?
Work?
Work also need to destress
what. Right, guys?
-Right, Right.
-I agree.
You’re right lah, Mr Seow.
Seow? What "Seow"?
Seow (siao) means 'crazy'.
What, "Mr Seow"?
Can you edit that part, please?
Everybody knows that it's nonsense.
Got virus, you just add the firewall.
If it’s a strong virus, you just
add a stronger firewall,
like have 2 walls instead of 1.
It’s common sense.
Everybody knows that.
For example, let’s say if you have
a cockroach in your house,
you won’t just move out of your house
or demolish your house, right?
You won’t, what.
You won’t. This one waste of time.
Okay, okay, tissue, tissue...$1.
Buy, lah, $1 only, $1.
Buy, lah. Why you don’t want?
Then you waste my time, for what?
Yeah, yeah...I know.
Wait, you mean...
Like that, my teacher
got no internet, ah?
Baik ke apa...
No internet, means they do work slower,
means they mark the paper slower,
means they give back the paper slower,
less homework means less stress, lah.
Thank you, teacher. Terima kasih!
Selamat Raya.
Hey, this is great...'live' TV. Sayang.
Despite this overwhelming divide
amongst Singaporeans,
one government agency
has indicated its absolute support.
For many years,
I have sent letters by post.
But of course I’ve never
received any replies,
but today, we have achieved
all that we’ve been working for.
Look at that, man, look at that.
Thanks to this no internet,
we will see an increase of people
coming to the parks
and actually enjoying nature.
You know, Singapore
got so much beauty,
why you keep looking
down at the phone.
Dey!
Look up, dey!
Look natural, dey.
Since the break of the news,
we’ve had some really
bad cases sent to us.
These internet addicts
did not take the news well,
but thanks to our 12-step internet
addiction programme,
we will achieve an
internet-free workplace!
Come sing with me,
No internet, no cry!
While it may take a while
to totally wean off
government employees
from the internet,
it seems that, whether we like it or not,
we will all find our ways of
accepting this, sooner or later...
As usual.
This is Andre Chichak,
The Noose.
And that brings us to the end
of this edition of The Noose.
I’m B.B.See.
Be sure to tune in again
next week for more of The Noose.
And don’t forget to book your tickets
to the second edition of
The Noose & Kakis Stage Show,
happening from May 19th to 21st,
at the MES theatre in Mediacorp.
My name is Xin Hua Hua.
Good night.
You did that last week.
Hey, I never stand here before
at the end of the show.
It's all about me.